没错  好鞋是关键
Yep, proper footwear is the key.
这地方有62英亩
This place is 62 acres.
我们一晚上要走三圈
We walk it three times a night.
如果足弓支撑不足
You do that with poor arch support,
你就死定了
you're a dead man. Y--
那是血吗
Is that blood?
嗯
Yeah.
而且延伸到坟墓那边
And it leads to that grave.
这是玩笑吧  欺负新人
This is a joke, right? Haze the new guy.
天呐
Oh, my God.
Oh, man.
我们在洛杉矶期间
So, there will be time to hit the beach
有时间去海滩吧
while we're in L.A., right?
不  我们是来了解我失踪那段时间的
No, we're here to learn about my missing time,
不是让你来晒黑的
not work on your tan.
相信我一点啊  爸爸
Oh, give me a little credit, Dad.
我没那么肤浅
I'm not that shallow.
我们是想勾搭个好帅哥
We were hoping to scope out some quality man candy.
冲浪男最性感了
Mm. Surfers are hot.
-你是个坏榜样  -谢谢
- You are a bad influence. - Thank you.
那不是恭...算了
That's not a c-- Never mind.
听着  韩国城就20分钟的路
Look, Koreatown's about 20 minutes away.
我待过的餐厅
The restaurant I was in
还得再过几个小时才开门
is not gonna be open for another few hours,
这样我们有的是时间安顿下来
giving us plenty of time to settle in.
-你好  理查德·卡塞尔  -回见
- Hi. Richard Castle. - Later.
我有预定
Reservation for...
还不赖
Hmm, not too shabby.
你喜欢就好
Glad you like it,
这里将是我们的基地
'cause this is going to be home base.
我和海莉上街调查
And you are going to be running it
你要在这里坐镇
while Hayley and I hit the streets.
-等等  不公平  -没办法
- Wait. That's not fair. - Too bad.
我们不知道会发现什么
We don't know what we're gonna find here.
我失踪期间还挨过枪子  记得吗
I was shot while I was missing, remember?
那可能就发生在洛杉矶
That could have happened in L.A.
你父亲说得对
Your father's right.
我们得到更多信息之前
Until we get more information,
我们得小心行事
we have to proceed with caution.
往好处看
Look on the bright side.
这世上还有比闷在一间有
There are worse places to be trapped
客房服务的五星级酒店更糟的事
than a five-start hotel with room service.
卡塞尔先生  我们拿来了您的行李
Mr. Castle, we've got your luggage.
很好  替我放进去吧
Great. Just, uh, put it right in there for me.
转念一想  我在这儿也行
On second thought, I'm good here.
或许我也陪你等
Maybe I'll wait with you.
这什么
What's this?
几分钟前信使送来给您的
Messenger dropped that off for you a few minutes ago.
信息
Thank you.
谁寄来的
Who's it from?
不知道
I'm not sure.
"卡塞尔先生  需要您的帮助
"Mr. Castle, your services are required.
好莱坞永恒公墓发现一具尸体
A body has been found at the Hollywood Forever Cemetery.
洛杉矶警局需要你帮助"
The LAPD needs your help."
署名是"GDS"
And it's signed "The GDS."
那是谁
Who's GDS?
最强侦探协会
The Greatest Detective Society.
那是什么
What's that?
就是最强侦探协会
It's the greatest detective society.
是个传奇性的组织
It -- It's a legendary organization.
据传
Rumor has it
亚瑟·柯南·道尔也曾是秘密会员
Sir Arthur Conan Doyle was a secret member.
而且  只是传说
And...it's a myth.
是老私家侦探告诉菜鸟的童话
It -- It's a fairy tale old P.I.s tell rookies
好骗他们干苦活儿
to get them to do the scut work.
你就是吃不着葡萄葡萄酸
Said the detective that didn't get an invitation.
好吧  不管真假
All right, real or not,
我们是来调查你失踪的时间  爸爸
we're here to investigate your missing time, Dad.
不是谋杀案
Not a murder.
是啊  但餐厅还有几小时
Right, but the restaurant doesn't open
才开门
for another couple hours.
而好莱坞永恒公墓就顺路
Hollywood Forever Cemetery is on the way.
看看也无妨吧
Can't hurt to take a look, right?
我们怎么进去
How are we gonna get in there?
这样吧  我们声东击西  你...
I've got it. You create a diversion.
打扰
Uh, excuse me.
你好  打扰
Hello? Excuse me.
打扰
Hey. Excuse me.
我找门德斯警探
Looking for Detective Menendez.
-他跟验尸官在一起  -谢谢
- He's, uh, with the M.E. - Thank you.
科特
Kurt!
海莉
Hayley.
我不知道你也来了
I did not know you were in town.
是啊  刚从纽约过来
Yeah. We just got in from New York.
这位是理查德·卡塞尔
This is Richard Castle.
科特·门德斯  重案组
Kurt Menendez -- Major Crimes Division.
-认识你很高兴  -我也是
- Great to meet you. - Likewise.
来"观光"的吗
Doing a little grisly sightseeing?
不是休息  完全是办事
Uh, no pleasure this time, just business.
办什么事
What kind of business?
得了  科特
Oh, come on, Kurt.
你懂的  客户保密什么的
You know the drill -- client confidentiality and all that.
但我们发现什么  都会告诉你
But anything we find, we'll share with you.
这话我听过
I've heard that one before.
是啊  但我做错了什么
Yes, but any failures on my part
一向都拿最好的纯麦芽威士忌赎罪了啊
have always been remedied with the finest single malt.
怎么样
So, what do you say?
让我们去看看啊
Will you let us in for a little look-see?
行吗
Yes?
-好吧  进来  -谢谢
- Sure. Come on. - Thank you.
谢谢
Thanks.
被害人是菲利普·哈里斯
Our victim's name is Phillip Harris.
本地私家侦探
A local private investigator.
验尸官说大概死于午夜  割喉
M.E. said he was killed around midnight -- throat cut.
凶手还挖了他的心脏
And then the killer took out his heart.
下手精准吗
Done with surgical precision?
不是很准
Not particularly.
纽约啊
So, New York, huh?
是啊  今早刚飞来
Yeah. Just flew in this morning.
有意思  被害人
That's funny, because our victim
昨天早晨刚从纽约飞回来
just flew back from New York yesterday morning.
我给住在那里的姐姐留了言
I left word for a sister who lives there.
疯狂的巧合
Crazy coincidence.
我跟纽约12分局
You know, I work very closely
有密切合作关系
with the 12th Precinct in New York.
莱恩和埃斯波西托警探
Detectives Ryan and Esposito.
他们可以替你去找哈里斯的姐姐问话
They could talk to Harris' sister for you,
或许在纽约查查线索
maybe run down any New York clues.
好啊  多谢  我给他们打个电话
Okay, thanks. I'll give them a call.
失陪
Excuse me.
代我问个好  他们可爱我了
Tell them I said hi. They love me.
卡塞尔
Castle?
他是个烦人鬼  但是个好人  好吧
He's a giant pain in the ass, but he's good people. Okay.
好  我们会帮忙的
Uh, yeah, sure. We'll help.
我们去找哈里斯的姐姐维罗妮卡问话
We'll interview Harris' sister, Veronica.
把案宗给我们发一份来吧
Yeah, why don't you send us a copy of the murder book, okay?
谢谢
Thanks.
我需要你帮个忙  不能告诉哈维尔
I need a favor, but you can't tell Javi.
我不知道这样好不好
I don't know if I'm comfortable with that.
不是坏事
It's not bad.
只是
It's just...
我认识了个人  我喜欢他
I met a guy. I like him.
我想让你给他做个背景调查
And I want you to run a background check on him.
-真浪漫  -真的
- Romantic. - Seriously.
就当今社会  谁都不可信
In this day and age, you can't trust anyone.
我不想爱上他
I don't want to fall for the guy
然后又发现他
and then discover he's got a thing
是个杀人狂
for putting the lotion in the basket.
好吧  我替你查查
Okay. I'll, uh, check it out.
查什么
Check what out?
我的红疹
Uh, this, uh... This rash that I have.
我想问问蕾妮的医学意见
Yeah, I wanted to get Lanie's medical opinion on it.
说太多了  哥们
Too much information, bro.
我也那么说  回见了
Yeah, that's what I said. Later, boys.
首先
First thing we need to do
我们得查到菲利普·哈里斯在办什么案子
is figure out what case Phillip Harris was working on.
他很可能是因此被杀
Odds are, that's what got him killed.
我也喜欢可怕的杀人案
Look, I love a gruesome murder as much as the next girl,
但我们没有客户
but we don't have a client.
而取悦那个可笑的最强侦探协会
And impressing that ridiculous detective society
并非我的首要任务
isn't exactly on the top of my list.
是我的首要任务
Well, it's on mine.
但首先看看是否有人知道
But first, let's see if anyone knows
我一年半前为什么要来这里
what I was doing here a year and a half ago.
嗯  肯定是这里
Yeah. This is definitely the place.
午餐两位
Two for lunch?
手表
The watch.
理查德  怎么回事
Richard. What's going on?
你18个月前就在这里
You were here 18 months ago.
是的  这是我的店  怎么了
Uh, yeah. It's my place. So?
你认得他吗
Do you recognize him?
不  我该认得吗
No, should I?
我来过
Uh, I was here about, um...
我大概一年半前来过
I was here about a year and a half ago.
出了什么事  你吼过我
Something happened. You yelled at me.
你是戴表那家伙
Oh, you're the guy with the watch.
什么表
What watch?
你拿不出钱
You -- You couldn't pay.
我本想报警的
And then I was gonna call the cops on you.
然后你把表给我作为抵押
And then, uh, you -- you gave me your watch to hold onto.
说你会回来取  但一直没回来
Said you were gonna come back for it, but you never came.
-我有跟谁一起来吗  -没有
- Was I with anybody? - Uh, no.
我有跟谁说话吗
Did I talk to anybody?
我有告诉你我去过哪或者要去哪吗
Did I tell you where I'd been or where I was going?
没有  你吃了饭  然后就走了
No. You, uh, just ate, and then you left.
还把表给了我
Uh, gave me your watch first.
还在你这儿吗
Do you still have the watch?
我最棒的一个助攻
Best wingman I ever had.
看上去不眼熟
That does not look familiar.
而且是假货
And it's a knock-off.
但这是我们最新的线索
But it's the freshest clue we have.
我要赎回来
I'll buy it back from you.
好吧
Sure.
我弟弟是对的
My brother was right.
什么对了
Right about what?
幽灵
The Phantom.
菲利普在追查的连环杀手
A serial killer Phillip was hunting.
他查一宗失踪案时偶然发现的
He stumbled onto it working a missing-persons case.
我们没听说过绰号幽灵的在逃连环杀手啊
We haven't heard of any active serials nicknamed The Phantom.
所以菲利普才喊他幽灵
That's why Phillip called him The Phantom --
因为都没人知道他的存在
because no one has any idea that he exists.
据菲利普说  幽灵一直在
According to Phillip, The Phantom had been
洛杉矶和纽约杀人
killing people in Los Angeles and New York
已经有几年了
for the last several years.
两岸连环杀手
A bicoastal serial killer?
菲利普飞回洛杉矶之前
Right before Phillip flew back to L.A.,
他说他查到了突破性线索
he told me that he'd had a break in the case,
他很快就能查明幽灵的身份了
that he was close to identifying The Phantom.
他肯定是太接近真相了
He must have gotten too close to the truth.
我调出了据说是幽灵杀害的人的尸检报告
I pulled autopsy reports on The Phantom's alleged victims.
共有七人  洛杉矶四名  纽约三名
Total of seven -- four in L.A., three in New York.
凶器都是刀
All seven were killed with a knife.
除了刀之外有其他规律吗
Any pattern besides the knife?
没有  被害人什么样的都有
No. The victims are all over the map.
四个男人  三个女人  种族和年龄都不同
Four men, three women. Different ethnicities and ages.
每个被害人都被割了点东西
Each of the victims had something removed --
耳朵  眼睛  手指
an ear, an eye, a finger.
为什么  这有什么重要
Why? What's the significance of that?
没有
There is none.
由于如此随机
And because of the randomness,
一直没人把这些案子联系起来
no one was able to connect the murders.
除了菲利普·哈里斯
Until Phillip Harris, of course.
那么菲利普是对的
So Phillip was right.
的确有名连环杀手
A serial killer's been hunting
在洛杉矶和纽约做案三年
in L.A. And New York for three years
而完全未被发现
completely under the radar.
跑这么远毫无进展
All this way for a dead end.
或许也好  无知是福
Oh, it might be for the best. Ignorance is bliss.
不  无知是地狱
No, ignorance is hell.
卡塞尔先生
Mr. Castle.
最强侦探协会要我去他们的总部
The GDS is requesting my presence at headquarters.
那么我一定是通过了他们的测试
This must mean I passed their test
他们要我加入他们
and they want me to join their ranks.
真不想戳破
I hate to burst your fanboy bubble,
但你怎么知道这没问题
but how do you know this is on the up-and-up?
-这没问题吧  -是  先生
- Is this on the up-and-up? - Yes, sir.
你干什么呢
What are you doing?
照看你
Watching your back.
我们有...
Uh, we have...
你好
Hello.
卡塞尔先生  希普顿女士
Mr. Castle, Ms. Shipton.
很荣幸认识二位
It's a pleasure to meet both of you.
我是梅森·伍德
I'm Mason Wood.
荣幸
What a pleasure.
我简直不敢相信我在这里
I cannot even believe I'm here.
这就是梦想成真
This is a dream come true.
多谢你这么说
That's very kind of you to say.
我们协会有悠久丰富的历史
Our society has a long and rich history,
我们的会员遍及各个大陆
and our membership expands every continent,
除了南极
save Antarctica.
-那里没几个杀人犯  -是啊
- Not too many murders there. - No. No.
不过  但我2007年发现了一艘藏在冰山里的
Although, I did find a lost Chinese treasure ship
失落的中国宝藏船
hidden in an iceberg -- 2007.
我也不想如此
Now, I hate to do this,
但我得单独跟卡塞尔先生谈谈
but I need to speak to Mr. Castle alone.
-你一定理解吧  希普顿女士  -不行
- I'm sure you understand, Ms. Shipton. - No.
如果需要  我可以留在这里
I can stay here, if that's what you mean.
太好了  这边请
Excellent. This way.
可以看到  我们召集来了几位会员
As you can see, we have assembled a few of our members.
我认得你
I know you.
你之前去了犯罪现场
You were at the crime scene.
你是个警察
You're a cop.
不  但我穿制服很像样
No, but I wear the hell out of a uniform.
这位是肯德尔·弗罗斯特
This is Kendall Frost.
她是位旧金山的私家侦探
She's a private detective based out of San Francisco.
我恐怕有点糊涂
I'm afraid I'm a little confused.
我们来这里究竟是做什么
What exactly are we doing here?
菲利普·哈里斯曾是我们协会的成员
Phillip Harris was a member of our society.
他的死是莫大的惨剧
His death is a tragedy.
但对你或者弗罗斯特小姐也是个机会
But it is also an opportunity for you or Ms. Frost.
菲利普的死让我们协会有了空位
Phillip's death has left an opening in our ranks.
你们之中破了他的案子的人  就可以受邀
Whichever one of you solves his murder will be invited in.
菲利普·哈里斯是对的
Phillip Harris was right.
的确有个在东西海岸
There is a phantom serial killer
杀人的幽灵连环杀手
murdering people on both coasts.
真聪明
That's clever.
分开下手
Splitting up his hunting ground
让大家不发现他
kept everyone from knowing his existence.
-他们查到线索了吗  -只有一条
- Did the boys get any leads? - Just one.
他姐姐说菲利普·哈里斯
His sister said that Phillip Harris
之前在顶点影业做卧底
was working undercover at Zenith Studios.
就是他们搞砸了
Oh, they're the ones
妮基·希特电影系列
that ruined the Nikki Heat movie franchise.
不是搞砸  是毁了  彻底毁了
Not ruined -- destroyed, terminated,
消灭  汽化  根除
extirpated, vaporized, eviscerated.
你想把所有近义词都说一遍吗
Do you plan on running through the full thesaurus?
不  差不多可以了
No. I think that'll about do it.
总之  菲利普认为
Anyway, Phillip thought
顶点影业的什么人就是幽灵
someone at Zenith Studios was The Phantom.
有可能
Makes sense.
很多跟电影业有关的人都东西海岸来回跑
Plenty of people connected with the film industry are bicoastal.
导演  制片人  摄影师
Directors, producers, cinematographers...
演员  他们都差不多是反社会
And actors, who are all borderline sociopaths, by the way.
这还用你说
Don't have to tell me.
顶点有人知道
Hey, did anyone at Zenith
菲利普是在那儿卧底吗
know that Phillip was working there undercover?
只有一个人  影业老板
Just one -- head of the studio.
我们去找他问话吧
Ah. Let's go talk to him.
谢谢
Thank you.
我肯定能得到
I am so going to get that spot
最强侦探协会的位置
in the Greatest Detective Society.
肯德尔肯定没办法
I mean, there's no way Kendall has access
知道我了解的那些信息
to the kind of details that I have.
别自大  里克  我们还没解决杀人案呢
Oh, don't get cocky, Rick. You haven't solved the murder yet.
-挡着我  -什么
- Hide me. - What?
干吗
How?
里克·卡塞尔
Rick Castle.
科特妮
Oh, hi, Courtney.
你好  我是科特妮
Hey. I'm Courtney.
海莉  怎么回事
Hayley. So, what's going on?
你们有仇吗
You guys have a beef or something?
-我和里克  -嗯
- Me and Rick? - Yeah.
不  怎么会  我们是好朋友
No. No way. We're buds.
是嘛
Oh. Buds?
我上次见到你时
Last time I saw you,
你差点开高尔夫车碾死我
you tried to run me down with a golf cart
就因为我不肯让你参与妮基·希特电影
'cause I wouldn't let you get cast in the Nikki Heat movie.
但我当时不知道  而现在知道的是
But what I didn't know then, which I do now,
你的电影大概是
was that your movie was gonna be
史上第一烂片了
quite possibly the worst movie ever made.
没有被选入你的电影
Not being cast in your movie
大概是对我的职业生涯最好的事了
was the best thing that could have happened to my career.
谢了  我们哪天一起吃午饭吧
So thanks. Let's do lunch some time.
-认识你很高兴  -嗯
- Nice meeting you. - Yeah.
替我给布兰登代好
Say hi to Brandon.
你能相信吗  史上第一烂片
Can you believe her? Worst movie ever made?
相信  那电影烂透了
Yeah, I can believe her. It was a terrible film.
都拜这个
Well, that was all thanks
笨蛋影业老板所赐
to this really obtuse studio executive.
他叫什么来着
What the hell was his name?
特雷夫·纳吉尔
Trevor Nigel.
你是理查德·卡塞尔吧
And you must be Richard Castle.
-是的  -我们以前只通过电话
- Yes. - We've only ever talked on the phone.
嗯  很高兴终于把脸和你的各种意见对上号了
Yeah. Nice to finally put a face to all those notes.
多谢你在没有预约的情况下同意见我们
Thank you so much for seeing us without an appointment.
开玩笑吗
Are you kidding me?
这就是命运  真的  里克
This is fate. I'm serious, Rick.
我们刚开的故事
Your name literally just came up
讨论会上才提到过你的名字
in our last story-development meeting.
是吗
It did?
听着  我知道  本影业
Now, look, I know this studio
在《希特袭来》的制作上很差劲
did a poor job producing Heatwave,
但相信我  我为你的规划努力争取来着
but believe me, I fought for your vision.
现在  我是影业老板了
And now that I am running the studio,
该继续做理查德·卡塞尔的生意了
it is time to get back in the Richard Castle business.
谢谢  我受宠若惊
Oh, uh, well, thank you. I'm flattered.
但我们其实不是为了我的书而来
But we're not actually here about my books.
我们是在调查菲利普·哈里斯的死
We're actually looking into the murder of Phillip Harris.
我听说了  令人震惊
Yes, I heard about that. It was shocking.
菲尔是个大好人
Phil was a great guy.
他几年前救了我一命
He saved my ass a couple of years ago.
拍到了我前妻
Got photos of my ex
跟我们的私人灵媒通奸的照片
having an affair with our personal psychic.
替我省了好几百万
Saved me millions.
菲利普的姐姐告诉我们
So, Phillip's sister told us
你准许他
that you gave him permission
在影业做卧底
to go undercover here at the studio.
是的  菲尔说他在办新案子
Yes. Phil said he was working a new case.
求我帮忙  我又欠他人情  就答应了
He asked for a favor. I owed him one, so I said okay.
他在调查谁
Who was he investigating?
他想接近奥斯汀·伊莱克拉
He wanted access to Austin Elektra.
那个电影导演
The movie director?
最新美剧下载
www.ZiMuZu.tv
是的  正在1号影棚拍片呢
Yeah. Shooting a film over on 1.
《角斗士》
"Gladiators."
能在中国挣大钱
It's gonna make a billion in China.
等等
Oh, h-hold on.
你不会觉得奥斯汀
You don't think that Austin
跟菲尔的死有关吧
had something to do with Phil's murder?
奥斯汀昨晚拍片了吗
Was Austin filming last night?
按计划是的
He was supposed to.
但不知为何
But for some reason,
他提前叫停了拍摄  然后离开了
he shut down production early and took off.
他什么时候离开的
About what time did he leave the lot?
听说是11点左右  怎么了
I heard around 11:00. Why?
那他有的是时间赶往公墓
Giving him lots of time to get to that cemetery.
1号摄影棚在哪
Where do we find Stage 1?
健身吗
You work out?
看啊  奥斯汀在那儿
Oh, look. There's Austin.
你打算怎么来
So, how do you want to play this?
如果是他杀了菲利普·哈里斯
Well, if he did kill Phillip Harris,
他肯定很小心  我们不能让他知道
he's bound to be on guard, so we can't let him know
我们把他当做嫌疑人
that we are looking at him as a suspect.
-肯德尔  -她真厉害
- Kendall?! - Oh, she's good.
她怎么会这么快就找到了奥斯汀
How did she get onto Austin so quick?
我们完了
We're done for.
她已经把他迷住了
She's already got him wrapped around her skinny, little finger.
别说我没为你做过什么
Don't say I never did anything for you.
你在这儿啊  亲爱的
There you are, darling.
你的新朋友是谁
So, who's our new friend?
亲爱的  这是奥斯汀·伊莱克拉
Babe, this is Austin Elektra.
我刚邀请你女友稍后去我家
So, I just invited your girlfriend up to my place later.
可以开始彩排了
Ready to rehearse.
如果你想也可以一起来
You're more than welcome to join if you want.
听上去挺有趣啊
Oh, that sounds naughty.
我就喜欢这个
I love naughty.
可以彩排了
Ready to rehearse.
我得走了
Got to go.
-今晚再见  -当然
- See you ladies tonight. - Absolutely.
你开什么玩笑
Are you kidding me with this?
得了  亲爱的
Oh, come on, sweetie.
爱和凶杀案调查都是无所不用其极的
All's fair in love and murder investigations.
你当这是游戏吗
What, do you think this is a game?
虽然你俩打架会很性感
As hot as it would be to see you two fight --
尤其是经过了那一吻
especially after that kiss --
我们得一起合作
we need to work together on this.
这样对我们都有利
It is in all our best interests.
好吧  我们合作
All right. We'll work together.
暂时的
For now.
这样正好
This is actually gonna work out great.
你和肯德尔缠住奥斯汀
While you and Kendall keep Austin distracted,
我就能去他家找出他是幽灵的证据了
I'll search his house for proof that he's The Phantom.
最强侦探协会的成员基本归我了
Membership in the GDS is as good as mine.
你倒是高兴了
Oh, yay for you.
怎么了
What's wrong?
是因为刚才跟肯德尔的吻吗
Was it the kiss with Kendall?
舌吻太多了吗
Was it -- too much tongue?
不够吗
N-- not enough tongue?
不怎么够
N-- Well, not enough.
不是这事  肯德尔说得对  这不是比赛
No, Kendall was right. This is not a game.
如果奥斯汀·伊莱克拉真的是幽灵
If Austin Elektra is in fact The Phantom,
那我们就真的是要进虎穴了
then we are walking right into the lair of a serial killer.
抱歉  "不够"后面的话再说一遍
I'm sorry. Repeat everything you said after "Not enough."
上帝保佑
Oh, God help us.
凯文
Hey, Kev.
怎么了  搭档
What's up, partner?
卡塞尔和海莉好像查到了些什么
Castle and Hayley might be onto something.
原来幽灵犯下两起谋杀案期间
Turns out that movie director was in New York
那个电影导演都在纽约
during two of The Phantom's murders.
那第三起呢
What about the third?
根据交易记录
Based on financials,
查不出那段时间奥斯汀在哪
there's no indication of where Austin was.
也就是说他有可能在纽约
Which means he could have been here
犯下了第三起凶杀案
committing that third New York homicide.
他可能就是凶手
This could be our guy.
是的  我会继续查的
Yeah, I'm gonna keep digging.
还有个事
Oh, and...
这是怎么回事  兄弟
what is this, bro?
你瞒着我什么
What are you hiding from me,
这个泰勒·罗斯是谁
and who is Tyler Ross,
还有你为什么要查他背景
and why are you running a background check on him?
他谁也不是
Tyler's nobody.
好吧  是这样  珍妮和我
Well, you see, okay, Jenny a-and I,
想要雇一个新保姆
we're looking to have a new nanny.
或者应该说  是男保姆
Or in Tyler's case, a -- a manny.
-什么  -是的
- What? - Yeah.
别装了
Stop it.
你简直太不会说谎了
You're, like, the worst liar ever.
这个人是谁
Who is this guy?
他是蕾妮的新男友
He's Lanie's new boyfriend.
她想让我查一下他  而且不告诉你
She wanted me to check him out but not to tell you.
你知道这意味着什么吧
You know what this means, right?
我们可以耍一下蕾妮了
We... are gonna have some fun at Lanie's expense.
蕾妮
Hey, Lanie.
我收到你的短信了
I got your text.
我给你找到凶器了
And I've got your murder weapon --
应该说是凶器的图片
a picture of it, anyway.
我利用幽灵所杀的人的验尸报告生成了这个
I used the autopsies of The Phantom's victims to generate this.
靠近底部的锯齿很特别
Those serrations near the base are pretty distinctive.
没错
Exactly.
找到这把刀
Find the knife...
就能找到凶手  干得漂亮
Find the killer. Nice work.
那个  背景查得怎么样了
So, how's the background check going?
目前很好
Oh, pretty good so far.
听到你这么说我不安心啊
I don't like the sound of that.
没有  没什么可担心的
No, t-there's -- there's nothing to worry about...
目前为止
y-yet.
只是有些传言
It's -- it's just a rumor.
说来听听
Let's hear it.
好吧  他对小丑有特别的
Okay. He's got a thing about...
感觉
clowns.
没事啊  很多人都怕小丑呢
That's okay. Lots of people are afraid of clowns.
不不不  他不是怕小丑
Oh, no, no. He's not afraid of them.
他喜欢小丑
He likes them.
成癖好了吗
Like a fetish?
天哪
Oh, good Lord.
我还没有查证这一点
I-I haven't verified it yet.
我还要去问问他的一个前任
I still have to speak with one of his exes.
好吧  有消息通知我  行吗
Okay. Keep me posted, will you?
莱恩  这太好了  谢谢你
Ryan, that is excellent. Thank you.
拖到明天早上再把它交给洛杉矶警察吧
Now, just hold off on giving it to LAPD just until morning.
我们有个计划来揪出幕后黑手
We have a plan to expose who's behind this.
或者害死自己
Or get ourselves killed.
打退堂鼓了吗
Having second thoughts?
跟一个从死者身上
About having a miage
取战利品的连环杀手会面吗
with a trophy-taking serial killer?
当然没有  怎么会出问题呢
No! What could possibly go wrong?
听我说  这就是凶器
Look, this is the murder weapon.
你们需要做的就是缠住奥斯汀  争取时间
All you have to do is distract Austin long enough
让我找到这把刀
for me to find this knife.
-希望它不要插在我们的背上  -嗯
- Let's just hope we don't find it in one of our backs. - Right.
抱歉
Sorry.
我采取了一些
I was setting up
反监控措施
a few counter-surveillance precautions.
你觉得我们被监视了吗
You think we're being bugged?
我们都不知道要去
We aren't sure exactly what or who
找谁或者找什么东西
we're looking for out here,
所以我觉得我们也不知道谁会在找我们
so I figured, we can't be sure who's looking for us.
那是什么引起了警报呢
So, what tripped the alarm?
可能传感器设置得太灵敏了
Maybe the sensor's turned up too high.
不是吧
I'll be damned.
看来这块手表
Looks like this watch is good for something
不是只能用来在韩国餐厅抵账的
other than taking care of checks at Korean restaurants.
找到了
Hello.
有人在手表的电池上
Someone has hard-wired a GPS transmitter
接了定位发射器
to the watch's battery.
你觉得是中情局吗
You think it's CIA,
泰国那次任务后留下的
left over from my Thailand mission?
有可能  不知道能不能查出来
Possible. Doubt we'll ever know for sure.
查不到这是在哪买的吗
Can't we track down where it was purchased?
查不到  这种发射器太常见了
No. I'm afraid this transmitter's incredibly common,
想要查出来简直是不可能的
which makes tracking it almost impossible.
那我们也要试一下  对吧
But we have to try, right?
这就是我们来这的初衷啊
I mean, it's why we're here.
肯德尔
Kendall.
你真是放好了鱼饵
You certainly have baited the hook.
没办法  特别是考虑到
I had to, especially considering
今天晚上是二对一
it's gonna be two against one tonight.
你说什么呢
What are you talking about?
拜托  里奇
Come on, Rick.
我知道你会趁
I know you're gonna sneak
我和海莉缠住奥斯汀的时候
into Austin's house to look for evidence
溜进他家找证据
while Hayley and I distract him.
我不傻  可是如果你觉得你没这个
I'm no fool, but you are if you think
就能成功的话  你就太傻了
your little plan will work without these.
奥斯汀·伊莱克拉家的结构图
Schematics to Austin Elektra's house.
你从哪搞到的
Where'd you get those?
你这漂亮的小脑瓜就别管这个了
Don't worry your pretty, little head about that.
漂亮吗
Pretty?
海莉和我缠住奥斯汀的时候
While Hayley and I distract Austin,
你要找到这个
you need to look for this.
这是一面假墙
It's a false wall.
一间密室
A secret room.
这一定是奥斯汀收藏他被害人
That would be the perfect place for Austin to hide
可怕战利品的绝佳地方
the grisly trophies he takes from his victims.
没错
Exactly.
如果你能找到奥斯汀是凶手的证据
Now, if you find evidence that Austin is the killer,
功劳由我们平分
I get equal credit.
不能诳了我
No double-crosses.
成交
Deal.
这样  梅森·伍德得把咱俩都
That way, Mason Wood has to make both of us
收为协会成员
members of the society.
走吧
Let's go.
等一下  你就穿成这样去吗
Hold on. Is that what you're wearing?
-是的  -不是
- Yes. - No.
让我想想是穿自己带来的
Deciding between something I brought
还是让里克再给我买一件
and something that Rick's about to buy me.
我想我知道你倾向于哪个选择
I think I know the direction you'll be leaning in.
你的确有资格加入最强侦探协会
You really do deserve to be in the Greatest Detective Society.
请进  请进
Come in, come in.
先来喝一杯
Let's get some drinks in you.
给
Here you go.
一些能让你放松的东西
A little something to loosen your inhibitions.
不用担心  我们已经很放松了
Oh, don't worry. We're plenty loose already.
等我把你绑起来就不会了
Not after I've tied you up.
谁先来
So, who's first?
要不这样
Tell you what.
让我先来绑你如何
Uh, why don't you let me tie you up first?
被绑住  我怎么进行
Then how am I gonna be able to do
那些计划好的坏事呢
all the terrible things that I've got planned for you?
我确定你会有办法的
Oh, I'm sure you'll figure something out.
不是吗  肯德尔
Isn't that right, Kendall?
肯德尔  肯德尔
Kendall -- Kendall?
该死
Damn it.
她要错过所有的乐趣了
She's gonna miss all the fun.
你上当了
You've been had.
那个该死的小
That dirty little...
我已经厌倦追着你跑了
I'm getting tired of chasing you.
休息片刻也无妨
Well, there's no rule against taking a short break.
怎么回事
What the hell?
你的朋友去哪了
Hey, where's your friend?
我以为我们说好的
Thought we had a deal.
不再互相欺骗
No more double-crosses.
抱歉  里克  不过我要成为
Sorry, Ricky, but I am going to be the one
扬名立万的那一个
to take those trophies in.
祝你好运
Well, good luck with that,
因为我在找一件谋杀凶器
because I'm looking for a murder weapon.
一种特殊形状的刀刃
It's a unique blade,
不过我想你并不知道这件事
but I guess you wouldn't know that.
-你说谎  -没有
- You're lying. - No.
它在这里
And here it is.
很好
Okay, great.
我们一起把它带走
We'll take it in together.
你说的  我们说好的  对吗
Like you said, we have deal, right?
所以现在说话又算话了吗
Oh, so now the deal's back on?
放下那把刀
Drop the knife!
奥斯汀  警察知道我们在这里
Austin, the police know we're here.
如果你杀了我们  他们会抓住你的
If you kill us, they will catch you.
我不会杀了你们
I'm not gonna kill you.
那你为什么拿枪口指着我们
Then why are you holding us at gunpoint?
因为你们在抢劫我
Because you're robbing me?
我们没有抢劫你
We're not robbing you.
我们在搜集你是连环杀人凶手的证据
We're getting evidence that you are a serial killer.
比如这把刀
Like this knife,
被用于七次仪式型谋杀中
which as been used in seven ritualistic murders.
你在说什么
What are you talking about?
我才不是连环杀人凶手  我是个电影导演
I-I'm not a serial killer. I'm a film director.
那是我两年前拍的一部恐怖片里的道具
And that is a prop from a horror movie I shot two years ago.
不管是不是道具
Well, prop or not,
这把刀的形状和我们受害者的伤口完全吻合
this knife matches our victims' wounds exactly.
那部电影一共做了五把一模一样的刀
There were five identical knives made for that film,
也就是说还有四把这样的刀在其他地方
which means there are four others out there just like it.
也许你应该去找那其中的一把
Maybe you should be looking for one of those.
但是其中三起谋杀你都在纽约
But you were in New York for three of those murders.
还有其他八百万人也在  包括我的助手
So were 8 million other people, including my assistant,
他可以证明我所有的行踪
who can prove my whereabouts at all times.
现在滚出我的房子
Now get the hell out of my house!
你可不可以...好吧
Do you think you could...okay.
导演说的是真话
Well, the director was telling the truth.
他在三起纽约谋杀中不在场证明都成立
His alibis check out for all three New York murders.
我们得去追查一下为那部恐怖片
Then we need to track down all the knives
做的所有的刀
that were made for that horror movie.
很显然其中的某一把
Yeah. Clearly one of them
被用来完成七次谋杀
was used to commit all seven murders.
八次
There were eight.
你在说什么
W-What are you talking about?
我发现了第四个纽约被害人
I discovered a fourth New York victim --
一个叫帕特·克鲁斯的人
a man by the name of Pat Crews.
你确定
Are you sure?
菲利普·哈里斯只知道三起
Phillip Harris only knew about three.
他漏掉这一起是有原因的
There's a reason he missed this one.
因为这起谋杀和幽灵在洛杉矶杀死一名女子
Because this murder took place on the same day
发生在同一天
the Phantom killed a woman in Los Angeles.
但这怎么可能
But how can that be?
除非
Unless...
有两个连环杀人凶手
There are two serial killers,
一边一个
one on each coast.
-谁啊  -我不知道
- Who is that? - I don't know.
不管是谁  我希望他们带了咖啡来
Whoever it is, I hope they brought coffee.
门德斯警探
Detective Menendez.
-要知道  -请进
- You know... - Please come in.
我想过会被
...I expect to be screwed over
某个不认识的蠢货坏事
by an asshat that I don't know,
但我没想到是被本该是朋友的人
but not from one who's supposed to be my friend.
我想你是听说了昨天晚上
I take it that you heard about what happened
在奥斯汀·伊莱克拉家发生的事情
at Austin Elektra's house last night.
你们说过会通知我案情进展
You said you'd keep me in the loop.
我们可以解释
Look, we can explain.
奥斯汀有一把符合凶器描述的道具刀
Uh, Austin had a prop knife that matched the murder weapon.
我们的实验室今天早晨检验了  不是它
And our lab tested it this morning -- it's clean.
你有去追踪一下
Did you manage to track down
这部电影里用到的其他四把刀吗
the other four knives used in the movie?
其中两把还在片厂室的仓库里
Two of the knives are still at the studio warehouse.
也不是它们
They came up clean, too.
据道具师说
And according to the prop master --
顺便说一句他的不在场证明已经核实
who alibied out, by the way --
最后的两把刀不翼而飞
the last two knives went missing.
蕾妮发现有两个不同的凶手
Well, Lanie discovered there are two different murderers
分别在各自的海岸用相同的凶器作案
operating on either coast using identical weapons.
我们所需要做的就是
All we have to do --
不  不  不
Oh, whoa, whoa. No, no, no.
没有什么我们  你们两个到此为止
T-there is no "We." You two are done.
如果我发现你们其中的哪一个继续查这个案子
And if I catch either of you working this case,
我就以扰乱公务的罪名逮捕你们两个
I'll have you both arrested for obstruction.
别别别
No, no, no, no. Mm.
也许一瓶小小的苏格兰纯麦威士忌
Hey, maybe a little single malt scotch
可以揭过这页
will smooth things over?
滚回去
Go home.
打扰一下
Excuse me.
这个刚送来是给你的  卡塞尔先生
T-this just came for you, Mr. Castle.
谢了
Oh. Um...thanks.
看起来门德斯不是唯一一个
Looks like Menendez isn't the only one
对昨晚感到不满的人
unhappy about last night.
梅森要立刻见肯德尔和我
Mason wants to see Kendall and me right away.
好运
Good luck.
那是什么
What's that?
这是报复
This is payback.
感谢前来赴约
Thanks for coming in.
其他人都去哪了
Where is everyone else?
他们对你俩的热情
Their enthusiasm for both of you waned
在昨晚的所作所为之后消退了
after the way you conducted yourselves last night.
简直杂乱无章  横冲直撞  缺乏我们期望
It was messy, boarish, lacking the sophistication
任何潜在会员所应有的心思缜密
we expect from any potential member.
-是她的错  -是他的错
- It was her fault. - It was his fault.
不  是我的错
No, it was my fault,
想着你们中会有一个
thinking that either of you
能接替菲利普
could ever have filled Phillip's shoes.
伍德先生  请再给我次机会
Mr. Wood, please. Give me another chance.
不  我来吧
No, give me another chance.
我会找到菲利普的杀手
I will find Phillip's killer.
她做不了  她这期间都落后我两步
She won't. She's been two steps behind me this whole time.
落后
Behind you?
我先找到奥斯汀的
I got to Austin first.
而我找到了那把刀
And I got to the knife.
虽然它不是真正的凶器
And although it wasn't the actual murder weapon,
但多亏我在纽约警局有联系人
thank you to my contacts at the NYPD,
我拿到了道具师的表弟在圣佩德罗的住址
I have the address to the prop master's cousin in San Pedro
他留了最后两把道具刀作纪念
who kept two of the last prop knives for himself as souvenirs.
怎么样
You see?
我只差一点了
I am close.
好
Okay.
希望最强侦探胜出
And may the best detective win.
别担心  我会的
Don't worry. I will.
你意识到她偷了你的线索吧
You realize she picked your pocket.
当然
Oh, yes.
那张纸上的地址是谁的
Whose address is on that piece of paper?
是个选角导演
It's a casting director
我妈想跟他见面
my mother wanted to have a meeting with.
肯德尔发现会气疯的
Kendall is going to be mad when she finds out.
像我怕她一样
Like I'm scared of her.
她是个武术大师
She is a master of Krav Maga.
一英里半开外使用狙击步枪游刃有余
And she is deadly with a sniper rifle from a mile and a half.
好运
Good luck.
我昨晚睡得很不好
I could not sleep last night.
一直做恶梦
I kept having nightmares
梦到我跟小丑波佐睡在一起
that I was sleeping with Bozo the Clown.
求你告诉我你有进展了
Please tell me you found out more.
别紧张  我跟泰勒前女友聊过了
Okay, relax. I spoke with Tyler's ex.
他对小丑没有特殊癖好
He does not have a clown fetish.
但
But...
怎么
But what?
怎么了  莱恩  快说
But what, Ryan? You better speak now.
他前女友提到说
His ex mentioned that
他好像是有个坏习惯
he might have a bit of a bad habit.
什么习惯
What kind of habit?
需要垫橡胶床单的那种
The kind that requires rubber sheets.
他尿床
He's a bed wetter?
门德斯警长来电
Detective Menendez just called.
据道具师称  拍摄结束那天
According to the prop master, those two knives went missing
那两把刀不见了
on the last day of the shoot.
他让片厂人员
He's got the studio
把从那天起的人员出入信息调出来
pulling drive-on logs from that day.
他会发复印件过来
He's gonna send us over a copy
我们就可以看看
so we can see if any of the names
有没有跟纽约谋杀案相关的人
connect to one of the New York murders.
你还好吗
Hey, you okay?
你跟她说了什么
Damn, what'd you tell her?
尿床
Bed wetter.
最好是有重要事情要说
This had better be important.
按摩师的手法
The masseuse was in the middle
简直如梦似幻
of doing things one only dreams of.
我调查了我爸手表里的跟踪器
I was able to trace the tracker in my dad's watch.
购买者是个名叫马尔科姆·麦凯布的男人
It was purchased by a man named Malcolm McCabe.
土生土长的洛杉矶人
Born and raised in L.A.
前陆军特种部队人员
Former Army Special Forces.
这里说他在海外工作
Says here he's working overseas.
他有个姑姑住在帕萨迪纳
He has an aunt that lives in Pasadena.
我们得去跟她聊聊  看她是否知道些什么
We should go talk to her, see if she knows anything.
当然  可以那么做
Sure, we could do that.
或者我们就假装你没找到这些
Or we could just pretend you never found this.
好吧
Fine.
但我爸想知道
But my dad wants to know
他失踪的时候发生了什么
what happened during his missing time.
当然了
Of course he does.
但当你父亲开始调查这位马尔科姆的时候
But what happens when your father starts
会发生什么
poking his nose into this Malcolm fellow?
我是说  这人是前特种部队人员
I mean, the guy is former Special Forces.
天知道他现在做什么工作
God only knows what he's doing for a living right now.
或许不记得发生了什么
Isn't it safer for your father
对他来说更安全  不是吗
to maybe not remember what happened?
你应该删了这些
You should delete this.
你还好吗
You okay?
我没事
Yeah. Yeah, I'm fine.
你继续去按摩吧
Why don't you head back to the spa?
这可用不着你告诉我
Don't have to tell me twice.
桃乐西·麦凯布  姑姑
所在地  帕萨迪纳
跟你说
Check this out.
我将片厂的人员信息
I compared the drive-on list from the studio
与纽约第四个被害人帕特·克鲁斯相关人员做了对比
to people connected to the fourth New York victim, Pat Crews.
有匹配的吗
Any matches?
克鲁斯曾是新学院的写作老师
Crews was a writing teacher at The New School.
他早期有个学生
One of his early students
现在是个成功的编剧  叫乔丹·基根
is a successful screenwriter named Jordan Keegan,
住在纽约
who now lives in New York
但他在洛杉矶片厂时
but happened to be on the studio lot in L.A.
碰巧凶器不见了
when the murder weapons went missing.
找到他这家伙吧
Let's pick his ass up.
你要做我侄儿马尔科姆的新闻报导吗
So, you're doing a news story on my nephew Malcolm, huh?
是关于战争英雄的
Mm-hmm. It's about war heroes.
看  他多帅啊
Oh. Look. Isn't he handsome?
但正如我所说  他出国了
But like I said, he's out of the country.
他工作很忙
His job keeps him really busy.
我给你他电话号码吧
Let me get you his number, okay?
-谢谢  -马上
- Thanks. - I'll be right back.
麦凯布女士  我要走了
Uh, Ms. McCabe, I have to go.
谢谢你的配合
Thank you for your time.
该死  阿丽克西斯  你跟你老爸一个样
Damn it, Alexis. You're just like your old man.
什么都不放过
You can't leave things alone.
你要杀了我吗
Are you going to kill me?
什么
What?
怎么会这么说
Why would you say that?
我不知道
Oh, I don't know.
也许是因为你跟我爸失踪有关
Maybe because you're connected to my dad's missing time
现在你又藏在我租车的后座上
and now you're hiding in the back of my rental car.
阿丽克西斯  我永远不会伤害你
Alexis, I would never hurt you.
不是你想的那样
This isn't what you think.
你到底玩的是哪出  海莉
What the hell is your game, Hayley?
相信我  你不会想知道的
Believe me, you don't want to know.
你父亲也是
Neither does your father.
为什么
Why not?
一言难尽
It's complicated.
乔丹·基根  我们得谈谈
Jordan Keegan? We need to talk.
谈什么
About what?
一宗谋杀案跟你扯上了关系
Well, your name came up in a homicide.
这是凶器
This is the murder weapon.
是你写的电影的道具
It's a prop from a movie that you wrote.
所以呢
So?
你有没有碰巧留把作纪念
So, did you happen to keep one as a souvenir?
又或是两把
Perhaps two?
一把你自己留着  一把给你在洛杉矶城外的同伙
One for yourself, one for your partner out in Los Angeles?
你俩在说什么
What are you guys talking about?
帕特·克鲁斯  你以前的写作老师
We're talking about Pat Crews, your old writing teacher.
他被一把跟那一样的刀杀了
He was killed with a knife shaped exactly like that one.
放下
Drop it!
救救我
Help me!
-快放了她乔丹  -退后
- Let her go, Jordan. - Stand back!
你无路可走了  把剪刀放下
You got no where to go. Drop the scissors.
听着伙计们  我是个作家
Listen, fellas, I'm a writer,
相信我  要是坏人投降的话
so trust me when I say if the villain surrenders,
这也太不过瘾了
oh, it's just so unsatisfying!
所以他们总是"死得其所"
That's why they always go out in style.
放松  乔丹
Just relax, Jordan.
别干蠢事
Don't do anything stupid.
蠢  我吗
Stupid? Me?
你怎么能这么说  这么多年把你们蒙在鼓里
How can you say that when we've outsmarted you for years?
"我们"是谁  你洛杉矶的同伙是谁
Who's "We"? Who's your partner in L.A.?
一个天才
A genius.
他信任我  将我的构想变成现实
He believed in me. Took my visions, made them real.
告诉我们名字  乔丹
Give us a name, Jordan.
你永远都找不到他
You'll never find him.
好的  没事  我理解  谢谢
Okay. No, I understand. Thank you.
是莱恩和埃斯波西托
That was Ryan and Esposito.
他们不得已杀了乔丹·基根
They had to kill Jordan Keegan.
但他们把乔丹电脑里的文件拷贝发过来了
But they sent us digital copies of Jordan's computer.
我觉得我们  "我们"是指你们两个
Now, I think we -- and by "We", I mean the two of you --
也许能在里面找到些什么
might be able to find something on there
可以给我们线索找到他在西海岸的同伙
that'll give us a lead to find his West Coast counterpart.
里克  我们得谈谈
Rick, we need to talk.
谈什么
About what?
你们俩单独谈谈
I'll give you two the room.
你还记得我们第一次见面的时候吗
You remember when we first met?
我怎么能忘呢
How could I forget?
你冷不丁冲我脸上打了一拳
You sucker-punched me in the face.
不  不是  我们之前就见过
No. No, we'd met before that.
确切地来说是一年半以前
A year and a half earlier, to be precise.
你是说整段时间以来你都知道
You mean this whole time you knew?
你到底是谁
Who the hell are you?
我是海莉  这个我没撒谎
I'm Hayley. Didn't lie about that.
严格来讲  我没有说过谎
Technically, I didn't lie about anything.
我确实隐瞒了事实  但我没说谎
I misrepresented, sure, but I-I didn't lie.
但是为什么呢
But why?
因为一年半前  是你让我这么做的
Because a year and a half ago, you asked me to.
实际上  是你求我这么做
In fact, you begged.
我不明白
I don't understand.
很久以前我在军情六处做自由职业工作
So ages ago, I did some freelance work for MI-6,
在一次任务中我遇见了一个美国间谍
and I met an American spy on an op.
他是个年长的绅士  很英俊聪明绝顶
He was an older gentleman, very handsome, smart as a whip.
我父亲
My father.
杰克森·亨特
Jackson Hunt.
一年半前  他找到我
Year and a half ago, he calls me,
让我在洛杉矶照看你
asks me to keep an eye out on you here in L.A.
说你在干涉一些你不该插手的事情
Said you were sticking your nose where it didn't belong.
他说我在做什么
What did he say I was doing?
我没问  他也没说
I didn't ask, he didn't say.
但我确实知道你在泰国呆了两周后
But I do know that after your two weeks in Thailand,
你在中情局的卧底任务就结束了
your undercover mission for the CIA was over
你本来应该回家的
and you were supposed to go home.
但你却依旧我行我素  去了洛杉矶
But instead you went rogue and you came to L.A.
为了监视你的去向
To keep tabs on you,
我从一个朋友马尔科姆那借了个定位跟踪器
I borrowed a GPS tracker from a friend of mine, Malcolm.
我把它安到了...
And I placed it --
我的手表里  是你
In my watch. That was you.
对  可你却把它留在了那家韩国餐馆里
Yeah, only you left it in that Korean restaurant.
所以我就失去了你的消息
So I lost track of you.
等我找到你时  你已经被人击中了
And by the time I found you, you'd been shot in the side.
谁开枪射我
Who shot me?
你不愿意说
You wouldn't say.
你确实提到了你在中情局的管理人
You did mention your CIA handler,
一个叫詹金斯的人
a guy named Jenkins.
你说你要走
You said that you were going to go and ask him
要让他把这里发生在你身上的一切清除
to erase everything that had happened to you here.
但这听上去不像是我的作风
But that doesn't sound like me.
我天性好奇  我为什么要那样做
I'm curious by nature. Why would I do that?
我也不知道  但你当时很坚定
I have no clue, but you were adamant.
你让我发誓说如果我再见到你
And you made me promise that if I ever met you again,
一定不会提起任何事
I'd never say any of this.
但这也不能解释你为什么待在我们身边
Well, that doesn't explain why you stuck around,
为什么你会同意跟我一起共事
why you agreed to come work with me.
我很喜欢你里克  我喜欢你的女儿
I'm fond of you, Rick, and I adore your daughter.
在过了一辈子只关心自己的生活后
And after a lifetime of caring about nobody but myself,
我决定留下来  看着你们两个
I decided to stick around and keep an eye on you two.
有点像菲利普·迪克的科幻小说
It's like a Philip K. Dick novel.
真希望我能回到过去
Wish I could go back in time
告诉我自己不要清除记忆
and tell myself not to erase my memory.
或许你可以相信你这么做是有原因的
Or you could trust that you did it with good reason.
也许你要对那段消失的时间放手
Maybe just let your lost time go,
因为如果你继续调查下去
because if you keep looking,
如果你坚持寻找答案
if you keep searching for that answer, well...
很难说你会捅出什么大麻烦
there's no telling what kind of hell you'll unleash.
爸爸
Dad?
海莉跟你说了什么
What did Hayley tell you?
真相
The truth.
为什么海莉要向我们说谎
Why did Hayley lie to us?
因为是我让她这么做的
Because I asked her to.
情况很复杂
It's complicated.
你能相信她吗
Can you trust her?
能  当然能
Yes. Absolutely.
你也可以
And you can, too.
但你不相信我可以处理好真相吗
But you can't trust me with the truth?
等等
Oh, hang on.
阿里克西斯  这跟信任无关
Alexis, that's not about trust.
我是你的父亲
I am your father.
从你降生到这个世界的那天起
And from the day you came into this world,
我就有了保护你的责任
it's been my job to protect you.
所以  我们下一步行动是什么
So, what's our next move?
没有下一步了
There is no next move.
我们不再惹麻烦了
We let sleeping dogs lie.
那样对每个人来说都更安全
It's safer that way, for everyone.
真的不好意思打扰你们
I'm really sorry to interrupt,
但我找到了一些东西
but I think I found something.
-关于杀害菲利普的凶手吗  -对
- On Phillip's homicide? - Yeah.
我在看乔丹·基根的电脑文件
I was going through Jordan Keegan's computer files,
我找到了些有趣的东西
and I found something interesting.
这是一个剧本
It's a screenplay.
《双生杀手》
"Gemini Killers."
这是个关于连环杀手二人组的恐怖故事
Yeah, it's a dreadful story about a serial-killing duo.
不是很确定  但也许能给我们一点启示
Not sure, but it might give us some insight.
我见过这个
I've seen this before.
这个剧本吗
The script?
不是  是边上的笔记
No, the -- the notes in the margins here --
这个奇怪的笔迹...
this odd handwriting that...
我知道凶手是谁了
I know who the killer is.
不  我拿不了  我...
No, I cannot hold. I...
我是特雷夫·纳吉尔
It's Trevor Nigel.
什么...你得把那挪走
What -- You're gonna have to move that.
特雷夫·纳吉尔你被逮捕了
Trevor Nigel, you're under arrest.
什么
Excuse me?
我们找到了杀害菲利普·哈里斯的那把刀
We found the knife that killed Phillip Harris.
还有一些相当可怕的人体部分
Along with a rather ghastly collection of human body parts.
我没有承认
I admit nothing.
你的同伙死前也没有
Neither did your partner before he was killed.
乔丹死了吗
Jordan is dead?
是他出卖了我  对吗
He gave me up, didn't he?
我就知道我不该跟个编剧合伙
I knew I should never have partnered with a screenwriter.
不  特雷夫  是你把自己出卖了
No, Trevor. You gave yourself up.
当你的片厂在拍《希特热浪》时
Back when your studio was doing Heat Wave,
对你交给我的那个烂剧本我提了建议
I gave you notes on that horrible script you commissioned.
但你却发了回来上面有手写的笔记
But you sent it back to me with a handwritten note
说我的想法很愚蠢
detailing why my ideas were stupid.
我永远不会忘记坏的评论
I never forget a bad review,
特别是你的字迹如此特别
especially one with such distinctive handwriting.
在你那连环杀手搭档的剧本上
It's the same handwriting
也出现了同样的笔迹
on your serial killer partner's screenplay.
理查德  你是个不错的作家
Richard, you're a pretty good writer,
但你真该读读乔丹的作品
but you should really read Jordan's work,
因为那实在是让人眼前一亮
because it is inspiring.
我读完他写的《双生杀手》的剧本之后
After I read his "Germini Killers" screenplay,
我就知道我找到了同路人
I knew that I had found a kindred spirit --
一个和我有着同样渴望的人
someone with the same desires as I had.
而他的剧本写出了
And his script laid out...
我们可以用来杀人的完美计划
...the perfect plan for us to kill --
完全不会引人注意
without attracting suspicion.
可惜  他总是写不好结局
Sadly, he could never nail the end.
我们猜到了  而你也走到了结局
Well, we did, and you've reached it.
也许可以由你可以改写他的剧本
Maybe you should do the rewrite.
打给我的助理约个时间
Call my assistant to set up a meeting.
算了吧
Know what? I'm good.
再说  我想你的下一部作品
Besides, I think your next picture's
应该是监狱情景剧了
gonna be a prison drama.
-还生我气呢  -是的
- Hey, still pissed at me? - Yep.
拜托
Oh, come on.
我下次来的时候补偿你
I'll make it up to you the next time I'm in town.
最好如此
You better.
你俩真甜蜜啊
That was really cute.
住口
Oh, stop it.
肯德尔
Kendall.
见到你真高兴  圣佩德罗好玩吗
Ha -- nice to see you. How was San Pedro?
那边车不多吧
Wasn't too much traffic, was there?
你开的那条路
What freeway did you take?
手段高明  卡塞尔
Well played, Castle.
你赢了  不公平但合理
You beat me, unfair and square.
好了
All right.
速战速决吧
Let's get this over with.
她人呢  她短信上说有要事
Where is she? Her text said it was important.
我不知道
I don't know.
那咱们走吧
Let's go, then.
你这是干吗
Hey! What'd you do that for?
我问了泰勒尿床的事
I confronted Tyler about his bed-wetting.
我们很抱歉  可以了吗
Hey, hey, hey! Look, we're sorry, okay?
一点也不可以
It's far from okay.
我们分手了
We broke up.
我们去找他谈谈  帮你们俩和好
Well, we'll talk to him. We'll work it out.
不用  是我提出的分手
No, I broke up with him.
他否认自己尿床
After he denied being a bed wetter,
但他承认自己有个癖好
he admitted to having a fetish for...
反正不是什么好事
Ooh, let's just say it was nasty.
怎么叫做不是好事
What do you mean, "nasty"?
这家伙到底有什么诡异的癖好
Yeah, what kind of nasty things was this dude into?
滚出我的停尸房
Get out of my morgue!
你们俩混球
Losers!
比赛结束了
The competition has ended.
理查德·卡塞尔
Richard Castle,
你破了菲利普·哈里斯的凶案
you have solved the murder of Phillip Harris.
谢谢  非常感谢
Thank you. Thank you very much.
你们太好了
You're too kind.
你证明了自己的能力
You have proven yourself worthy,
而我们最强侦探协会的会员们
and we, the members of the Greatest Detective Society,
决定邀请你加入我们
offer you a place at our table.
我受宠若惊
I'm humbled and flattered,
-但我恐怕要拒绝你们的好意了  -什么
- but I'm afraid must decline. - What?
你这是干吗
What are you doing?
这可是一辈子只有一次
This is a once-in-a-lifetime opportunity
能跟精英中的精英共事的机会
to work with the best of the best.
对我来说不是
Not for me.
我已经在和世界上最优秀的警探一起共事了
I already work with the greatest detective in the world,
我等不及回家回到她的身边了
and I cannot wait to get back home to her.
但是  你们应该认真考虑
But, sir, you should seriously consider Kendall
让肯德尔加入
for membership.
她是位出色的侦探
She is one hell of a detective
而且非常精明
and sneaky in all the right ways.
你确定吗
You're sure about this?
非常确定
Absolutely, sir.
你越来越有意思了
You just keep getting more and more interesting,
卡塞尔先生
Mr. Castle.
我会留意你的
I'm gonna have to keep an eye on you.
好了
Okay.
你还没收拾好东西吗
Are you not packed?
我做不到
I can't do it.
收拾衣服吗
Pack you clothes?
我做不到就这么走开
Walk away.
海莉  我需要知道到底发生了什么
Hayley, I need to know what happened to me.
好吧  还有最后一件事
Okay, there's one last thing.
就在你去消除记忆之前
Just before you left to get your memories erased,
你带着最后一个请求来找我
you came to me with one final request.
什么请求
Like what kind of request?
如果你要求知道真相的话
That if you demanded to know the truth,
我就给你看这个
I show you this.
这是什么
What is this?
黑网上一个秘密网址
It's a, uh, secret website on the dark web.
里面有什么
What's on it?
不知道
Not a clue.
你设了一个只有你自己知道的密码
You installed a password that only you would know.
称之为"布莱尔的密码"
Called it "Blair's combination."
那是我十七岁时写的一个短故事
From a short story I wrote when I was 17.
从来没有发表过
Never saw the light of day.
密码是什么
What was that combination?
4左
4 left...
17右
17 right...
21左
21 left.
我出去了
I'll step out.
不  不  你
No, no. You've, um...
你有权一起看
You've earned the right to see this.
伙计  是我
Hey, there, buddy. It's me.
应该说  是你
And by "me," I mean you.
如果你看到这个视频的话  说明你是个蠢货
And if you are seeing this, then you are an idiot,
因为你试图搞清楚
because you are trying to figure out
在洛杉矶发生了什么
what happened to you in Los Angeles.
你查出的关于布莱肯
What you discovered about
和洛克塞特合作的事
Bracken's partnership with LokSat
太过危险了
is too dangerous to pursue.
洛克塞特
LokSat?
我知道洛克塞特的事
I knew about LokSat?
我差点没命就是很好的例子
I am barely living proof.
我中枪是因为我试图查出
I was shot trying to figure out
洛克塞特的航班今晚在哪降落
where LokSat's plane was landing tonight.
我差一点就被发现而命丧虎口
I barely escaped without being identified.
我清除咱们的记忆是有原因的
I am erasing our mind for a reason --
为了保护凯特
to protect Kate.
因为如果她发现了
'Cause if she found out,
她就会没命
then she will die.
所以为了她好  不要告诉她
So do not tell her what you discovered in Los Angeles,
你在洛杉矶的发现
for her sake.
你知道这意味着什么吗
Do you know what this means?
是的  你追踪到了洛克塞特
Yes. You tracked LokSat.
如果我们可以查到机场记录
If we can cross-reference airports
确定你中枪当晚都有哪些航班降落的话
and identify what airplane landed the night you were shot,
我们就很有机会
then we have a real chance
查出洛克塞特究竟是谁了
of finding out who LokSat really is.
不  不
No, no.
这意味着发生的一切都是我的错
It means what happened was my fault.
贝克特之前同事的遇害
The murders of Beckett's former AG team --
为了保护贝克特不受洛克塞特的伤害
in trying to protect Beckett from LokSat,
我无意中给他们都判了死刑
I inadvertently sentenced them all to death.